<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  Settlement Image Mapping Configuration

  This file maps settlement IDs and names to their corresponding city images.
  Images are used in both Settlement detail views and Codex entries.

  Attributes:
  - id: Database settlement ID (if known)
  - name: Settlement name (used for matching)
  - imagePath: Path relative to /public/Images/Cities/
  - thumbnailPath: Optional smaller version for cards (falls back to imagePath)
  - faction: Associated faction name
  - type: Settlement type (city, town, outpost, etc.)
  - description: Short description for Codex entries
-->
<settlements>

  <!-- Major Cities -->
  <settlement id="1" name="Apex Reach" imagePath="/Images/Cities/Apex_Reach.png" faction="Solar Dominion" type="city">
    <description>A towering metropolis reaching toward the eternal dusk sky, Apex Reach stands as the pinnacle of Solar Dominion achievement. Crystal spires pierce the clouds while advanced technology powers every aspect of city life.</description>
    <lore>Founded in the early days of the Solar Dominion's expansion, Apex Reach was designed to showcase the faction's technological prowess and architectural ambition. The city serves as both a symbol of power and a center of innovation.</lore>
    <population>15000</population>
    <founded>Year 1100</founded>
  </settlement>

  <settlement id="2" name="Haven's Ring" imagePath="/Images/Cities/Havens_Ring.png" faction="Twilight Alliance" type="city">
    <description>A circular fortified city built in concentric rings, each layer providing protection and organization. Haven's Ring embodies the Twilight Alliance's philosophy of balanced defense and community structure.</description>
    <lore>Constructed as a refugee sanctuary during the Great Fracture, Haven's Ring grew from a temporary shelter into a thriving metropolis. Its unique circular design allows for efficient defense while maintaining strong community bonds.</lore>
    <population>12000</population>
    <founded>Year 1050</founded>
  </settlement>

  <settlement id="3" name="Harmony's Edge" imagePath="/Images/Cities/Harmoneys_Edge.png" faction="Twilight Alliance" type="city">
    <description>Perched on the boundary between light and shadow, Harmony's Edge perfectly embodies the Twilight Alliance's core values. The city's architecture blends natural elements with careful engineering.</description>
    <lore>Built at the precise geographical location where dusk is most prominent, Harmony's Edge serves as a philosophical and strategic center for the Twilight Alliance. The city's location allows it to harness unique natural phenomena.</lore>
    <population>10000</population>
    <founded>Year 1120</founded>
  </settlement>

  <settlement id="4" name="Peak Sanctuary" imagePath="/Images/Cities/Peak_Sanctuary.png" faction="Umbral Order" type="fortress">
    <description>A fortified mountain stronghold carved into living rock, Peak Sanctuary provides impregnable defense and commanding views of the surrounding territories. Dark stone architecture blends seamlessly with natural caves.</description>
    <lore>The Umbral Order discovered ancient caverns within the mountain and expanded them into a massive fortress city. The natural defensibility combined with strategic location makes Peak Sanctuary nearly impossible to assault.</lore>
    <population>8000</population>
    <founded>Year 1080</founded>
  </settlement>

  <settlement name="Peak Sanctuary Alt" imagePath="/Images/Cities/Peak_Sanctuary2.png" faction="Umbral Order" type="fortress">
    <description>An alternative view of the Peak Sanctuary complex, showing the extensive underground network and vertical construction that characterizes Umbral Order architecture.</description>
    <lore>Beneath the visible fortress lies an extensive network of tunnels, chambers, and underground cities that house the majority of Peak Sanctuary's population and strategic resources.</lore>
  </settlement>

  <settlement id="5" name="Last Hope Undercroft" imagePath="/Images/Cities/Last_Hope_Undercroft.png" faction="Deep Dwellers" type="underground_city">
    <description>A vast underground metropolis illuminated by bioluminescent fungi and carefully managed light sources. Last Hope Undercroft represents the Deep Dwellers' mastery of subterranean living.</description>
    <lore>When surface conditions became untenable, the Deep Dwellers excavated massive caverns and created a self-sustaining underground civilization. The Undercroft now rivals surface cities in population and technological advancement.</lore>
    <population>18000</population>
    <founded>Year 1030</founded>
  </settlement>

  <!-- Industrial Centers -->
  <settlement id="6" name="Solar Dominion Industrial Hub" imagePath="/Images/Cities/Solar_Dominion_Industrial_Hub.png" faction="Solar Dominion" type="industrial">
    <description>A massive industrial complex showcasing the Solar Dominion's manufacturing capabilities. Smoke stacks and factory towers dominate the skyline as production runs day and night.</description>
    <lore>Built to centralize manufacturing and resource processing, the Industrial Hub produces everything from basic goods to advanced military equipment. Its efficiency is legendary across all factions.</lore>
    <population>7000</population>
    <founded>Year 1140</founded>
  </settlement>

  <settlement id="7" name="Twilight Alliance Bio-Manufacturing" imagePath="/Images/Cities/Twilight_Alliance_Bio-Manufacturing.png" faction="Twilight Alliance" type="industrial">
    <description>A unique blend of biological and technological manufacturing, this facility produces organic-tech hybrid products. Green spaces integrate seamlessly with production areas.</description>
    <lore>The Twilight Alliance developed bio-manufacturing as an alternative to purely mechanical production. The facility demonstrates their commitment to balanced development and sustainable practices.</lore>
    <population>5000</population>
    <founded>Year 1150</founded>
  </settlement>

  <settlement id="8" name="Umbral Order Mining Facility" imagePath="/Images/Cities/Umbral_Order_Mining_Facility.png" faction="Umbral Order" type="mining">
    <description>A grim industrial mining complex carved into mountainsides, extracting rare minerals and precious metals. The facility operates continuously with military precision.</description>
    <lore>The Umbral Order discovered rich mineral deposits in the shadow mountains and built this facility to exploit them. Mining operations are conducted with ruthless efficiency and strict discipline.</lore>
    <population>4000</population>
    <founded>Year 1110</founded>
  </settlement>

  <settlement id="9" name="Deep Dwellers Salvage City" imagePath="/Images/Cities/Deep_Dwellers_Salvage_City.png" faction="Deep Dwellers" type="salvage">
    <description>Built among ancient ruins and technological debris, Salvage City specializes in recovering and repurposing lost technology. Scavengers and engineers work side by side.</description>
    <lore>The Deep Dwellers established this settlement atop ruins from a pre-Fracture civilization. Through careful excavation and salvage operations, they've recovered countless technological marvels and ancient knowledge.</lore>
    <population>6000</population>
    <founded>Year 1090</founded>
  </settlement>

  <!-- Fallback/Default -->
  <settlement id="default" name="Unknown Settlement" imagePath="/Images/Cities/Havens_Ring.png" type="settlement">
    <description>A settlement in Dusk Meridian. Image not yet available.</description>
  </settlement>

</settlements>
